hi everybody this is keys indoors
video number four this tutorial is about
implementing inventory mechanics into
your maze prototype
it will introduce us to the hud and a
process of manipulating basic objects
we will use a key to open a door but
remember a key could be anything
a ham sandwich a shotgun or a memory and
so could a door
a hungry dog a jealous lover or a
fragile psyche
the first magic trick is this we need an
object in the game world we're going to
see an object in the game world
and we're going to move towards it and
when we get close enough it will vanish
and then when we press a when we it will
save the idea that we are carrying it
and when we press a key and i we can
show an inventory that shows that we
have it
the second magic trick is that when the
player comes upon a door
and is carrying the key the door opens
automatically
and if they're not carrying the key they
get a message so for starters
let's prepare some fonts for messages
and some graphics for
our objects so we're going to import a
font
so you can make your own font i am today
i'm going to import a font from dafont
and we will use today we'll use the
first thing we see daily hours
and i'm going to save this file
so at this point
i want to go to my project folder
on my desktop that contains my adventure
i'm going to go into content
i'm going to create a directory called
fonts
if i don't have one created already and
i'm going to take that file
and we'll put it in the directory i will
right click and extract all
and we'll extract
and uh that's it for the internet for
now
uh it is daily hours so it's a ttf file
so now if we have opened our adventure
i'm keeping up
i'm keeping a shortcut on my desktop for
open our adventure
we'll see that if we placed it anywhere
in our content file
unreal engine already knows that it's a
kind of file type that it recognizes
so we're going to click to import and
click yes all
okay and
so we go if we go under content we see
under my fonts
the daily hours is here we can double
click on daily hours and have a look at
it
and down here down in the bottom here
that's the actual preview of the font
itself
okay so we can create increase that size
if we want to i'm going to go up to
under runtime font legacy font size
i'll go up to 20 we can see a little bit
better
and save and then minimize
okay so now if we want to test it out
i've created a folder under content for
widgets
so go under my widgets and
create a widget so right click under
user interface
widget blueprint and i'm going to call
this
widget test test
and it's going to be a widget that i'm
going to use to test
uh fonts and things like that okay
so here i'm going to put the text under
the palette
select the text object and place it on
the canvas panel
so it becomes a job of the canvas panel
select it you might have to move in a
little bit
and then move your text object
i'm going to move mine roughly to the
center of the screen
and i'll change this to
i'll keep that the same
so now we want to apply our font to it
so i'm going under under appearance
font where it says roboto let's go under
here
and let's select the font that we that
we added
and now scroll in and we can see that
our font works
i'm going to increase the size here
and you'll notice under under this
appearance
there's a few things that you might want
to take note of color and opacity
so i'm going to select a color let's uh
i'm going to create a color
let's go in the purple area
now when you're creating a color design
for prototype it might it's
sometimes nice to um have a kind of
repertoire of colors so i'm going to
take that swatch i'm going to put it up
there so now it's
now it's there other times i want to use
that purple
maybe in other places maybe in objects
and things like that
good and i'll click ok
and other things we want to have a look
at
let's go move change the justification
to center
and i'm going to scroll down a little
bit we'll have a look
this flower in the upper left hand
corner that's the anchor
so this will this will be a reference
for the playback screen
and it's important because sometimes you
will
not see things in previewing because
they're anchored in odd places
and you'll think you're doing something
with the widget but you just can't see
it when you're previewing
and the other situation that comes up is
if you have
a design that's going out to multiple
different platforms
like a mobile screen is different than a
computer screen and so you might have
objects anchored to the side an
inventory anchored to the side for
example
and it doesn't show up because it's
anchored to the wrong size for the
mobile
that sort of thing so compile
and save and so now we have a widget we
can test
so i'm going to test this widget i'm
going to open the level blueprint
i'm going to right click keyboard
and i would like to do test it with a
t for test so keyboard c
to test the widget when it's pressed
i want to create a widget
the widget class that i want to create
is the test
that we just created
i'm going to drag out of the return
value this is a little shortcut to add
it to the viewport
and click add to viewport here
and you see it automatically connects
both
compile and save
and now when we play if we click
t it adds our block to the viewport
now the second thing that we want to be
able to do is we only want to be able to
use our font
for objects that are in the world not
just
on the view screen in front of us not
just on the hud
so i'm going to add a text object text
render object excuse me to the world
and you can see that this
object has text on it if i select it
character oops i select the character
where are you
we should be able to see the text i'm
going to move a little bit so that we're
right in front of it
yeah it's a little dim isn't it
and i will turn it around it should just
look backwards it's fine
but i will rotate it
and it's just not very bright there it
is down there
i'm going to bring it up a little bit
and i'm going to make it larger than
this larger text
so we'll go texture under color let's
give it
purple like we had before and now
let's create go to world size and make
it a little bit larger
okay and save
so now we can see it
let me play a little bit easier okay
so now if we want to change that to our
new font
we go to here and if we
uh put there ours was called daily hours
we put it there we noticed that there's
nothing there
that's because unreal engine uses a
system called distance fields and this
economizes on computation during ray
tracing
and provides a lot of other benefits
in terms of reduction of data and since
we're creating a 3d object
and there's nothing to say that this 3d
object can't be a mile long
in unreal world it needs to have
the ability to do distance fields
so
uh let's go ahead and let's find the
font on the browser
and i'm going to go to my fonts daily
hours
there's the daily hours font i'm going
to duplicate
it so i'm going to have two versions of
this font one for widgets and one for
the world
and i'm going to use the word distance
field
just like the system does
so that i can search for it
easily in any of the in any list that
comes up
okay so now let's open it up and
the first thing we need to do is to
try to
open uh make it a a
distance field font we need to go
offline to do it okay
changing the case type will cause this
font to reinitialize that's what we're
doing we're going to this kind of older
form of
representation here and let's go and
let's find
our font was called
daily hours now watch this is going to
fail
so we're looking for daily hours you'll
see it
now let's search explicitly for it daily
hours
daily hours
okay and we see that it's not there so
this is by
this is because uh trying to go offline
we're not able to use the font that we
imported
so what we need to do is we need to take
this font
and we need to install it in in the
operating system
so i'm going down it's on the different
screen but i'm telling you what i'm
doing
i'm in the lower left hand of the screen
in the search bar
and i'm typing font settings
so now this will bring up our font
settings
and i'm copying that
and we can see down here the daily hours
is now installed
so now i'm going to go back to unreal
engine
and go to our distance field font
click offline click yes
and now look for daily hours
and there it is daily hours i'm going to
make it a little bit bigger
and bring it in and there's our font
daily hours
so now that we have access to it
in offline we're going to re-import it
but we're going to re-import it with the
distance field
so let's go down to
offline font import options
use distance field alpha check that
okay and now we are going to go under
asset and we are going to reimport daily
hours font distance field
and now it has generated a version that
we can use in space
so let's save
and close that
and now we'll go back to our make sure
our text render object system
is selected excuse me and
under font for the text render object
let's use our distance field version
and there it is it pops right in
save and we will play that's what it
looks like
so we've now customized our font we have
a font that we can use
that will make our game look a little
bit special to us
okay and then the next thing we're going
to do for setup
is we are going to scan and prep our
graphics
so i'm going to go out of unreal engine
and i'm going to go into the
at this point
and i'm going to bring in
a graphic that i have created that has
some inventory objects
that i want to play with so
i put it into the project
your content and i have a my scans
directory
and this is what this looks like
excuse me so these are black and white
black and white pictures i made for some
things that i might
want to use so we're going to have a key
to open a door today
uh here's a sandwich for a dog here's a
letter i don't know what the letter is
for yet but this is just to this is
we're just
making a prototype so we're just using
this to learn
how to make a more complicated inventory
and
i'm going to have have you meet a
character i think
so i've drawn pictures prototype
pictures for these things so that we'll
have something to put in our digital
version of our game
and so let's go ahead and i'm going to
take that skin and i'm going to drag it
right in
drag it right into all right so i'm
not going to change the size of these
things
i'm going to scale them in unreal engine
but i am going to
[Music]
break them apart and add an alpha
channel so
we see that with our entire scan
selected i'm going to make sure that
it's everything is
selected with ctrl a under colors
i'm going to click color to alpha and it
has correctly guessed that i want to
remove the white so i'm going to click
ok now i am going to start
breaking this apart into individual
graphics here's a key
i'm going to go ahead and select the
rectangular select tool
and copy
and ctrl v to paste floating selection
is here i'm going to call this key
and enter so now
i have this key on its own layer
so let's do that for each of our other
objects
sandwich
and i'll call this a letter
okay uh you see what happened is that i
had the wrong thing selected i didn't
even though i saw it on the screen
i didn't have the correct i didn't have
the correct thing selected so we
accidentally pasted the sandwich
again so now with the scan selected i
want to select the letter
i'm going to remove this layer right
click
delete layer so now with the scan
selected i do the select
copy v
lighter goes return and that's all that
we need to get today
so i'm going to close that
and let's export these as graphics i'm
going to go to the key
make sure that layer is selected i'd
like to rotate this a little bit
so i'm going to go under the uniform
transform
and if i transform right click rotate
i rotate my key a little bit so because
when i see it on the screen
i want to
go ahead and click rotate and i'm going
to do the same thing for the sandwich
i'm going to select the sandwich layer
the unified transform we're on the
rotate tool because we've already
selected
it and i'm going to rotate that sandwich
and rotate and now the same thing for
this letter
i'm going to click the letter we have
the tool ready
and rotate the letter
these are very best pictionary skills to
select these things
okay the key is now selected i'm going
to
kind of approximate a square selection
here because this is going to be
the proportions of the tile we'll use so
with that selected
i'm going to go under layer i'm going to
go under image excuse me
and fit canvas to selection and so now
we have a roughly square
thing that we can use i think maybe
i think maybe make it exactly square
just so we know and now image
good canvas to selection much better i'm
going to move the key i'm going to
select
but with the move tool i'm going to move
the key a little bit
all right so now the key is going to be
transparent
uh in the background but it'll be much
easier to see if we fill it in with some
kind of
some kind of coloring so i let's i'm
going to use white
for today so it looks more prototypey
and i'm going to select the bucket tool
if you don't see some of the tools that
i'm finding
go under under tools and make sure that
the tools that you want are there or you
can even just open them from there
okay so i'm going to take this bucket
tool so it'll take this color
it will fill in that key there we go
there's a nice textured looking thing
that we got by me using the eraser too
soon and smearing the
and smearing the ink i'm going to save
this project so we're not saving the
graphic here we're just saving the
project
and i'm going to save this in
in the same folder the same unreal
engine folder
an xcf file is a is a file
and i unreal engine just won't see it
but we can still have it as part of our
project
so i'm going to call this inventory
items and click save
okay and so now i'm going to start
exporting graphics so i'm going to
under file export as
i'm going to put this in content under
my objects
and uh these are old versions of
doing this exercise so i'm going to call
this
excuse me
inventory one
key
export and using the png file
rather than jpeg or gif that will
make sure that we have that transparency
ready for us
and let's just double check in unreal
engine that it's done what we want
so i just clicked over to unreal engine
i'm going to go ahead and click import
and now under content by objects
inventory in key that's the one we're
using
that's the one i use just for
demonstration invo1
key and we can if we double click we can
[Music]
open
you